Finding Aid for Office of Undergraduate Admissions (University of Michigan) publications, 1911-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Office of Undergraduate Admissions (University of Michigan) publications 1911-2001 1956-2001
University of Michigan. Office of Undergraduate Admissions.
0718 Bimu 2
Newsletters, reports, brochures produced by the Office of Undergraduate Admissions. The record group includes administrative materials, applications, information on recruitment programs, transfer and application guides, recruiting videotapes, and admissions data reports.
2.5 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Received from the unit (donor no. 9029 .)
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The Office of Undergraduate Admissions (University of Michigan) publications record group is open without restriction.
The Office of Undergraduate Admissions was created in 1954 as part of a reorganization of the Registrar's office coinciding with the retirement of long-time registrar Dr. Ira Smith. The new office, headed by the Director of Admissions, was responsible for the selection of all freshmen admitted to the University and the admission of transfer students to the College of Literature Science and the Art, College of Pharmacy, School of Education, School of Music and School of Nursing. The office handled the admission process and undertook a variety of recruitment programs. Clyde Vroman was named the first Director of Admissions.
Newsletters, reports, and brochures produced by the Office of Undergraduate Admissions at the University of Michigan. The record group includes administrative materials, applications, information on recruitment programs, transfer and application guides, and admissions data reports aimed at prospective students, admitted students, transfer students, international students, high school guidance counselors, as well as faculty and staff.
The record group contains the following series: Administrative, Admitted Students, Applying and Transferring, Outreach and Marketing, and Recruitment.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Office of Undergraduate Admissions.; Transfer students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; International students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; College students--Recruiting.
Genre Terms:
Videotapes.
- Administrative 1987-1995
  The Administrative series (1987-1995, 0.2 linear feet) includes various newsletters and reports about the admissions program, including undergraduate admissions data reports for 1994 and 1995.
  - Admission Research Questionnaire undated (Box 1)
  - Internal newsletters 1989-1991 (Box 1)
  - Points of Entry (newsletter), 1987-1992 (Box 1)
  - Recommendations for Improving Enrollment Management, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate Admissions Data
    - 1994 (Box 1)
    - 1995 (Box 1)
- Admitted Students 1968-2000
  The Admitted Students series (1968-2000, 0.2 linear feet) includes packets of information, newsletters, and preparation materials for newly admitted students.
  - Admitted Student Material 1990-2000 (Box 1)
  - Campus Day 1988-2000 (Box 1)
  - Michigan News, 1986-1988 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter for Admitted Students, circa 1990-1991 (Box 1)
  - U-M Converses (Newsletter), 1968-1973 (Box 1)
- Applying and Transferring 1956-2001
  The Applying and Transferring series (1956-2001, 0.4 linear feet) includes materials intended for students interested in applying and transferring to the University of Michigan. Materials include application forms, bulletins and informational brochures about the University, as well as guidelines for transferring.
  - Applying
    - Admission of Freshmen (Information for Prospective Freshmen, Information for New Students, 1911/1912-1980 (Box 1)
    - Application forms 1985-1992, undated (Box 1)
    - Bulletins, v.1 (1970)-v.30 (2001), 5 folders (Box 1)
    - Information for Applicants, 1982-1985 (Box 1)
    - International Admissions Information 1992-1997 (Box 1)
    - Prep Notes: College Preparation Guide (Box 1)
  - Transferring
    - Admission of Transfer Students, 1958-1980 (Box 1)
    - Community College Bulletin, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
    - How to Get Here from There: A Handbook for Community and College Counselors, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Students with Foreign Academic Experience, 1980s (Box 1)
    - Transfer Information undated (Box 1)
- Outreach and Marketing 1985-1997
  The Outreach and Marketing series (1985-1997 and undated, 0.2 linear feet) primarily includes promotional brochures, flyers, leaflets, and videotapes about the University of Michigan aimed at prospective students.
  - Brochures, leaflets, flyers
    - Consider Michigan 1985 (Box 1)
    - Flyers and miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Game Plan for Returning Students (Box 1)
    - General and Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    - Picture Yourself at Michigan (Box 2)
    - Posters (Box 2)
    - Publications packet 1997 (Box 2)
    - Visitor's Guide (Box 2)
    - WCC, Marygrove (Box 2)
  - Videotapes
    - Consider Michigan!, circa 1987 (Box 2)
    - The University of Michigan, undated (Box 2)
- Recruitment 1956-1992
  - Alumni
    The Recruitment series (1956-1992, 0.9 linear feet) contains materials aimed at recruiting students, including materials for high school guidance counselors, alumni, and reports and brochures of special recruitment programs. This series contains several volumes of "career guide leaflets," which gives basic information about individual departments, schools, and colleges.
    - Alumni Recruiting Handbook, 1985/1986-1988 (Box 2)
    - Alumni Resource Handbook, 1988-1992 (Box 2)
  - High School Recruitment
    - Career Guide leaflets (also called Guide for Planning an Education)
      - July 1963, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - March 1965, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - October 1970, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - October 1974, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - October 1982, 1 volumes (Box 2)
      - October 1983 (Box 2)
        (table of contents only)
      - Miscellaneous and general (Box 2)
    - Freshman Admission Summaries
      - 1982/1983 (Freshman Admission 1983 A Report to Principals and Counselors) (Box 3)
      - 1984/1985 (Freshman Admission: Summary for 1984-1985) (Box 3)
      - Summary Information Folders 1984-1990 (Box 3)
    - Michigan Highlights (newsletters), 1994-1996 (Box 3)
    - Principal-Freshman-Counselor Conferences 1956-1969, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Recruitment Programs
    - Ambassador Program (Box 3)
    - The Cook Family Foundation Gift May 1984-May 1991 A Summary of the Recruitment and Enrollment of Students from Outstate Michigan through the Cook Project, 1991 (Box 3)
    - Evaluation Reports of Special Recruiting Activities, 1977-1980 (Box 3)
    - Evaluation of Special Recruitment Programs, 1982-1983 (Box 3)
    - Evaluations of Special Recruitment Programs
      - 1984-1985 (Box 3)
      - 1985-1986 (Box 3)
    - Opportunity Award Program (Box 3)